One shot is all it takes
Dear Wendy is a comedy, crime, drama film directed by Thomas Vinterberg.
In a blue-collar American town, a group of teens bands together to form
the Dandies, a gang of gunslingers led by Dick Dandelion.
Following a code of strict pacifism at odds with the fact that they all carry guns, the group eventually lets in
Sebastian, the grandson of Dick's childhood nanny, Clarabelle, who fears the other gangs in the area.
Dick and company try to protect Clarabelle, but events
transpire that push the gang past posturing.
Dick Dandelion, played by Jamie Bell.
Krugsby, played by Bill Pullman.
Freddie, played by Michael Angarano.
Sebastian, played by Danso Gordon.
Clarabelle, played by Novella Nelson.
Huey, played by Chris Owen.
Dear Wendy is a 2005 crime film directed by Thomas
Vinterberg and written by Lars von Trier.
It stars Jamie Bell, Bill Pullman, Michael Angarano, Mark
Webber, Danso Gordon, Novella Nelson and Alison Pill.
It was an international co-production between Denmark, Germany, France,
and the United Kingdom, filmed on-location in Copenhagen.
The film had its world premiere at the 2005 Sundance Film Festival.
Vinterberg won the Silver St.
George for Best Director at the 27th Moscow International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of underdog, friendship,
secret society, west virginia, pacifist.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.